<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on bhuv&#39;s notebook</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on bhuv&#39;s notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Are inhouse LLMs really cheaper than APIs?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/is_inhouse_llm_cheaper_than_api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/is_inhouse_llm_cheaper_than_api/</guid>
      <description>In the rapidly evolving landscape of Large Language Models (LLMs), organizations face a crucial decision: should they deploy their own in-house models or rely on third-party API services? This analysis delves into the cost and performance dynamics of both approaches, leveraging detailed examinations of token-based latency and throughput.&#xA;Understanding Token Dynamics in LLMs Tokens are the fundamental units processed by LLMs, encompassing words or subword units. The number of input tokens (prompt length) and output tokens (generated text) directly impact computational resources, latency, and overall costs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to cache your functions the right way?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cache_functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cache_functions/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Benchmarking&amp;rdquo;—a word that either kicks off an experiment or follows a bold new proposal. But when you&amp;rsquo;re dealing with massive datasets, the benchmarking and evaluation functions can take their sweet time. What&amp;rsquo;s a reasonable person to do? Simple: hit run, grab a coffee, lunch, or, if you&amp;rsquo;re really daring, take a nap. Yet, the horror of returning to find your entire experiment crashed because one row was invalid, an API hit its rate limit, or some sneaky corner case reared its ugly head is all too real.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
