<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About in yaml on bhuv&#39;s notebook</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About in yaml on bhuv&#39;s notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Are inhouse LLMs really cheaper than APIs?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/is_inhouse_llm_cheaper_than_api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/is_inhouse_llm_cheaper_than_api/</guid>
      <description>In the rapidly evolving landscape of Large Language Models (LLMs), organizations face a crucial decision: should they deploy their own in-house models or rely on third-party API services? This analysis delves into the cost and performance dynamics of both approaches, leveraging detailed examinations of token-based latency and throughput.&#xA;Understanding Token Dynamics in LLMs Tokens are the fundamental units processed by LLMs, encompassing words or subword units. The number of input tokens (prompt length) and output tokens (generated text) directly impact computational resources, latency, and overall costs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to cache your functions the right way?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cache_functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cache_functions/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Benchmarking&amp;rdquo;—a word that either kicks off an experiment or follows a bold new proposal. But when you&amp;rsquo;re dealing with massive datasets, the benchmarking and evaluation functions can take their sweet time. What&amp;rsquo;s a reasonable person to do? Simple: hit run, grab a coffee, lunch, or, if you&amp;rsquo;re really daring, take a nap. Yet, the horror of returning to find your entire experiment crashed because one row was invalid, an API hit its rate limit, or some sneaky corner case reared its ugly head is all too real.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeepSPInN-multimodal Deep learning for molecular Structure Prediction from Infrared and NMR spectra</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/pub04/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/pub04/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Molecular spectroscopy studies the interaction of molecules with electromagnetic radiation, and interpreting the resultant spectra is invaluable for deducing the molecular structures. However, it is a strenuous task that requires highly specific domain knowledge. DeepSPInN predicts the molecular structure when given Infrared and 13C Nuclear magnetic resonance spectra without referring to any pre-existing spectral databases or molecular fragment knowledge bases. DeepSPInN does this by formulating the molecular structure prediction problem as a Markov decision process (MDP) and employs Monte-Carlo tree search to explore and choose the actions in the formulated MDP.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient and enhanced sampling of drug‐like chemical space for virtual screening and molecular design using modern machine learning methods</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/pub02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/pub02/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Drug design involves the process of identifying and designing novel molecules that have desirable properties and bind well to a given target receptor. Typically, such molecules are identified by screening large chemical libraries for desirable physicochemical properties and binding strength with the target protein. This traditional approach, however, has severe limitations as exhaustively screening every molecule in known chemical libraries is computationally infeasible. Furthermore, currently available molecular libraries are only a minuscule part of the entire set of possible drug‐like molecular structures (drug‐like chemical space).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Reinforcement Learning for Molecular Inverse Problem of Nuclear Magnetic Resonance Spectra to Molecular Structure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/pub01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/pub01/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Spectroscopy is the study of how matter interacts with electromagnetic radiation. The spectra of any molecule are highly information-rich, yet the inverse relation of spectra to the corresponding molecular structure is still an unsolved problem. Nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) spectroscopy is one such critical technique in the scientists’ toolkit to characterize molecules. In this work, a novel machine learning framework is proposed that attempts to solve this inverse problem by navigating the chemical space to find the correct structure given an NMR spectra.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern machine learning for tackling inverse problems in chemistry: molecular design to realization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/pub00/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/pub00/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: The discovery of new molecules and materials helps expand the horizons of novel and innovative real-life applications. In pursuit of finding molecules with desired properties, chemists have traditionally relied on experimentation and recently on combinatorial methods to generate new substances often complimented by computational methods. The sheer size of the chemical space makes it infeasible to search through all possible molecules exhaustively. This calls for fast and efficient methods to navigate the chemical space to find substances with desired properties.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plas-5k: Dataset of protein-ligand affinities from molecular dynamics for machine learning applications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/pub03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/pub03/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Computational methods and recently modern machine learning methods have played a key role in structure-based drug design. Though several benchmarking datasets are available for machine learning applications in virtual screening, accurate prediction of binding affinity for a protein-ligand complex remains a major challenge. New datasets that allow for the development of models for predicting binding affinities better than the state-of-the-art scoring functions are important. For the first time, we have developed a dataset, PLAS-5k comprised of 5000 protein-ligand complexes chosen from PDB database.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
